etas.com 2013-03-24

# ETAS - Terms of Use / Privacy Policy

With these Internet pages, the ETAS Group would like to provide you with a comprehensive source of information for all our products and applications. 

##  Privacy Policy 

**Personal Data**  
When you visit our website you may be asked to give us personal information such as your name, postal or e-mail addresses or telephone number. If you give us personal information, that information will be treated confidentially and maintained in accordance with applicable law including the laws of the States of Illinois and California. This data is used within the ETAS Group in automated processes for the handling of your inquiries or for advertising purposes only with your explicit authorization. The processing adheres to all national and international protection of privacy regulations. We will not pass on, lease, or sell the data to any third person. External service providers are included in some processes and the data may be made available to them. In such a case, we guarantee that your data is treated with utmost care and only for this required purpose. You may rescind your authorization for the use of your personal data at any time. Please send your written request via postal mail to our Data Security Officer (DSO) using the company address shown below in the imprint. You may also contact our Data Security Officer for any other comments or concerns regarding personal data. Additional terms and conditions regarding the processing of your data may also be provided to you before you sign up for a particular service. 

**Cookies**  
In order to provide a customized, personal service, ETAS Group may use cookies to store and help track your information. Cookies are small files of information that are stored on your computer's hard drive for future reference. You can reset your browser either to notify you when you receive a cookie, or to refuse to accept cookies. Please note that cookies let you use our services more easily and let us keep track of certain statistical information that helps us improve our site. Certain areas of some sites may not function properly if you reject a cookie. 

**IP addresses**  
An IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer whenever you are surfing on the web. We use IP addresses to analyze trends, administer the site, track user's movement, gather broad demographic information for aggregate use and compile statistics that show the daily number of visitors as well as the daily requests received for particular files. 

##  Legal Disclaimers 

**Content and Links of the Web site  
** The information in our Internet pages was created with great care. However, we do not take any responsibility for the completeness and correctness of the data. We update the information and downloads continuously and they may be changed or deleted by us at any time without notice. The content of the Internet pages of the ETAS Group is protected by copyright. The information may be used for private, not commercial, purposes, and by journalists for editorial purposes. When reproducing the content, please refer to the property rights of the ETAS Group. All contents may be used on other Web pages, networked computer systems, or electronic media only with written permission of ETAS GmbH. Distribution, demonstration, or reproduction for commercial or public purposes is prohibited. Any violation is subject to immediate destruction of all printed or downloaded contents; the ETAS group reserves the right to possible further claims for damages. All downloading is at your own risk. The ETAS Group is not responsible for any damages which may occur through the installation and use of the software or the Web contents, as legally admissible. All files were screened for viruses at the time they were made available for downloading from our Web site. 

**Links and Cross References**  
The ETAS Group Web site contains links to third party websites. At the time the link is established, we verify the legality of the content of these Web sites. ETAS GmbH and the ETAS Group are not responsible for any illegal content that you may access through any of our links. ETAS Group does not assume any liability for the performance, quality, accuracy, timeliness, reliability, or any other aspect of products or services on these websites. ETAS Group is neither responsible for third parties' legal or privacy policies nor for their processing of personal data. When we receive notice of any illegal content of linked pages, we will attempt to remove the link, as long as it is technically possible and reasonable. 

**Global Validity**  
The ETAS Group Web site may contain references or links to products, services, or offers of third parties which may not be available, or legally permissible in your country. Such references do not imply the intent of the ETAS Group to provide such information or offers to your country. 

**Security of Active Contents  
** The ETAS Group Web site contains some active content. The scripts and automated Web pages used by us are screened to detect possible hazards. During this process, no personal information is gathered and your privacy is protected. For statistical purposes, data is gathered to determine the behavior of the visitors to our Web site. This data is processed anonymously and deleted afterwards. 

##  Quality Policy 

**Customer**  
In concert with our own, our customers‘ expectations set the standard for the quality of our products and services. We measure our success by our customers‘ evaluation of ETAS. 

**Reliability**  
We are a reliable partner for our customers. 

**Responsibility**  
It is the responsibility and goal for all of us to meet the customers‘ expectations. 

**Prevention**  
We avoid quality problems through the usage of prevention. 

**Responsiveness**  
If quality problems occur, our response is fast and constructive, and we eliminate the cause. 

**Continuous Improvement  
** Our processes do help us to meet the requirements. We continuously improve their quality and adapt them fast to new requirements with the active participation of all of us. 

**Suppliers**  
Our suppliers contribute substantially to the quality of our products and services. Therefore, our suppliers must live up to the same high quality standards we have adopted. 

##  Principles of Work Safety and Environmental Protection 

**Sustainability**  
We accept that our actions must accord with the economy, the environment, and the responsibility we take for the community at large, also with a view to future generations. For this reason, respect for people’s health and safety, or an economic use of resources, and for a natural and clean environment are basic principles of our business policy. 

**Responsibility**  
It is the task of all associates to help prevent the endangering of people and the environment, as well as to maintain strict compliance with all laws and regulations relating to work safety and the protection of people’s health and the environment. It is a leadership task to recognize such dangers, to evaluate them, and to undertake appropriate actions. 

**Products**  
We develop and manufacture products that are safe, environmentally, and efficient. Our products enhance people’s safety and reduce burdens to the environment, also at their subsequent recycling and disposal. 

**Processes**  
We design processes to ensure that – wherever economically feasible – people’s health and safety have priority and that effects on the environment are kept to a minimum. We are prepared to cope with emergencies. This is also the spirit in which we cooperate with suppliers of goods and services. 

**Continuous Improvement  
** We review our processes and our behavior on a regular basis, just as we measure their effects on people and on the environment. This is how we identify weak points and potential for improvement, and ensure the effectiveness of our program for work safety and protection of people’s health and the environment. 

##  Copyrights 

If not stated otherwise, ETAS is in possession of all utilized trademarks and copyrights. Third parties may use these trademarks, logos, or hallmarks only with explicit written permission. 

© 2003-2012 ETAS GmbH, Stuttgart, Germany as of 17.09.2004 

##  Imprint 

The contents of these Web pages are published by ETAS. If you have any questions, suggestions, or criticism, please contact: 

ETAS GmbH  
Borsigstr. 14  
70469 Stuttgart  
Germany  
Phone: +49 711 89661-0  
Fax: +49 711 89661-106  

Represented by the Management Board: Friedhelm Pickhard, Philipp Rose, Uwe Hillmann  
Commercial Register: Amtsgericht Stuttgart HRB 19033  
VAT ID No.: DE811679830 

© 2003-2012 ETAS GmbH, Stuttgart, Germany.
